<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN"
 "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd">

<html>
<head>
<title>Project Gutenberg Australia December 2008 Newsletter</title>
</head>
<style>
<!--
* {
	font-family: "Courier New";
	font-size: 10pt;
  }
p {
  margin: 1.5em 0;
  }
-->
</style>

<body>

<p>PROJECT GUTENBERG OF AUSTRALIA<br>
==============================</p>

<p>MONTHLY NEWSLETTER - DECEMBER
2008 [includes details of ebooks placed online during November 2008]</p>

<p>Dear Avid Reader,</p>

<p>Copyright laws are changing all over
the world. Be sure to check the copyright laws for your country before
downloading or redistributing ebooks mentioned in this newsletter.</p>

<p>CONTENTS:<br>
---------------------------------------<br>
* News and Reviews<br>
* Last month's postings<br>
* Other Information (including details of how to unsubscribe)</p>

<p>NEWS AND REVIEWS<br>
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>CHRISTMAS CHEER<br>
---------------</p>

<p>It is a little early for Christmas
items but we can't hold them over until next month or they will be a little
late. And, of course, any&nbsp;newsletter worth its salt must have a bumper
Christmas edition. Below are&nbsp;some stories and poetry to get you in the
Christmas spirit.</p>

<p>Here, in Australia, Christmas falls
in summer. My childhood memories are of baked 'dinners' (for lunch or the
evening meal)...cricket in the back yard, or in the street in front of our
house...welcoming the southerly breeze which sometime came along in the
afternoon and which was heralded by the banging of the front door. Am I just
imagining it, or have those southerlies stopped blowing?</p>

<p>The writers below express many
different facets of Christmas in Australia. If you enjoy the extracts, the
entire ebook is but a mouse-click away.</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>A short extract from: 'That Pretty
Girl in the Army,' from &quot;Children of the Bush,&quot; by Henry Lawson&quot;
<a href="http://freeread.com.au/ebooks/e00107.txt" rel="nofollow">http://freeread.com.au/ebooks/e00107.txt</a></p>

<p>We had dinner at Billy Woods's
place, and a sensible Christmas dinner it was--everything cold, except the
vegetables, with the hose going on the veranda in spite of the by-laws, and
Billy's wife and her sister, fresh and cool-looking and jolly, instead of being
hot and brown and cross like most Australian women who roast themselves over a
blazing fire in a hot kitchen on a broiling day, all the morning, to cook
scalding plum pudding and redhot roasts, for no other reason than that their
grandmothers used to cook hot Christmas dinners in England.</p>

<p>And in the afternoon we went for a
row on the river, pulling easily up the anabranch and floating down with the
stream under the shade of the river timber--instead of going to sleep and
waking up helpless and soaked in perspiration, to find the women with
headaches, as many do on Christmas Day in Australia.</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>The entire ebook &quot;Children of
the Bush&quot; <a href="http://freeread.com.au/ebooks/e00107.txt" rel="nofollow">http://freeread.com.au/ebooks/e00107.txt</a>
from which the above story was taken, is worth reading. It&nbsp;includes the
story 'The Ghosts Of Many Christmases,' which is a little long to include
here.]</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>This extract is provided for the
description of Christmas, but you may wish to access the full ebook and
read&nbsp;further <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0606851h.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0606851h.html</a></p>

<p>An extract from: &quot;The Convict Laundress&quot; by Mary Theresa Vidal</p>

<p>It was a bright, clear day--how
bright, how blue, and how clear, none but those who have been out of the
British isles can understand. It was Christmas day; but instead of frost and
snow, and cold, and leafless trees, and blazing fires, there was intense heat,
and the trees looked, as they always do in Australia, a dingy blueish tint, but
still full of leaf and blossom: and here and there, where marks of cultivation
peeped through the interminable forest or bush, there were strips of the
brightest green maize, refreshing indeed to the eye, and contrasting pleasantly
with the brown grass, and the tall white trunks of the gums. The house, or
rather weather-boarded cottage, was four or five miles from the settlement,
where there was a wooden church. Thither the family had repaired on this
morning. There was but one service, for the clergyman proceeded to another
congregatation eight miles beyond. There had been beef and plum pudding for
dinner, the government men, or convicts, partaking in the Christmas fare; and
there were thoughts of those far away, and many a lingering regret for the old
associations of the season. Yet as the evening breeze sprung up, and stirred
the gums and acacias, and breathing through the cottage refreshingly cool, the
spirits of all rose, and with one accord they went out into the forest at the
back of the house. The merry voices were echoed round and round, and I could
see the farm-servants and working men as they strolled under the trees. Every
one being out, I went to the back, to see that all was safe. There was a large
waste piece of ground with the men's huts, the stables and barn, and nearer the
house stood the kitchens and store. Two or three dogs lay about, the poultry
were busy picking up their food, and a pet cockatoo came jumping up to my side,
begging for a bone in its peculiarly unharmonious voice. As I stood, feeling
rather lonely, I heard a dull, melancholy noise; it came from the kitchen. I
thought every one had been out: I listened again. Yes, it was from the kitchen,
and it was certainly some one in grief: heavy sobs and a low moaning formed a
strange contrast to the distant sounds of mirth and merriment!</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>'Tangmalangaloo' by John O'Brien appeared in the June 2008 Newsletter. I 
repeat it here so that yo do not need to look for it. 
<a href="http://www.gutenberg.net.au/newsletters/200806-newsletter.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.gutenberg.net.au/newsletters/200806-newsletter.html</a></p>

<p>TANGMALANGALOO</p>

<p>The bishop sat in lordly state and
purple cap sublime,<br>
And galvanized the old bush church at Confirmation time.<br>
And all the kids were mustered up from fifty miles around,<br>
With Sunday clothes, and staring eyes, and ignorance profound.<br>
Now was it fate, or was it grace, whereby they yarded too<br>
An overgrown two-storey lad from Tangmalangaloo?</p>

<p>A hefty son of virgin soil, where
nature has her fling,<br>
And grows the trefoil three feet high and mats it in the spring;<br>
Where mighty hills uplift their heads to pierce the welkin's rim,<br>
And trees sprout up a hundred feet before they shoot a limb;<br>
There everything is big and grand, and men are giants too--<br>
But Christian Knowledge wilts, alas, at Tangmalangaloo.</p>

<p>The bishop summed the youngsters up,
as bishops only can;<br>
He cast a searching glance around, then fixed upon his man.<br>
But glum and dumb and undismayed through every bout he sat;<br>
He seemed to think that he was there, but wasn't sure of that.<br>
The bishop gave a scornful look, as bishops sometimes do,<br>
And glared right through the pagan in from Tangmalangaloo.</p>

<p>&quot;Come, tell me, boy,&quot; his
lordship said in crushing tones severe,<br>
&quot;Come, tell me why is Christmas Day the greatest of the year?<br>
&quot;How is it that around the world we celebrate that day<br>
&quot;And send a name upon a card to those who're far away?<br>
&quot;Why is it wandering ones return with smiles and greetings, too?&quot;<br>
A squall of knowledge hit the lad from Tangmalangaloo.</p>

<p>He gave a lurch which set a-shake
the vases on the shelf,<br>
He knocked the benches all askew, up-ending of himself.<br>
And so, how pleased his lordship was, and how he smiled to say,<br>
&quot;That's good, my boy. Come, tell me now; and what is Christmas Day?&quot;<br>
The ready answer bared a fact no bishop ever knew--<br>
&quot;It's the day before the races out at Tangmalangaloo.</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>An extract from: The Letters of Rachel Henning <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0607821.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0607821.txt</a></p>

<p><br>
Exmoor,<br>
December 27th 1862</p>

<p>My Dearest Etta,</p>

<p>I wrote to you last on the ninth of
this month. Biddulph took the letters with him to Port Denison, whence he meant
to start by the steamer for Brisbane, but after waiting a week in the Port,
which he describes as the dullest, hottest and generally most detestable little
town he ever saw, it became evident that the steamer had missed this trip, so
he came home last Monday, to our great surprise, when we thought he was at
Rockhampton at least.</p>

<p>The steamer is expected again next
week, and he is going off again tomorrow to meet her. I hope he will be more
fortunate. It is very inconvenient that the Murray is so uncertain, as it is
nearly a hundred miles from here to Port Denison. I expect you will get several
of my letters together, but if so you must be sure and read those of the
earliest date first, and then they will not be so stupid, but will come in the
form of a journal.</p>

<p>I am writing now chiefly to
acknowledge your seventeenth of September letter, which reached me on the 13th
of this month. You see, you may reckon on your letters generally taking three
months to reach us.</p>

<p>Christmas Day is come and gone. It
was an unexpected pleasure to have Biddulph back here to spend it with us, and
though we were but a small party we were tolerably jolly. The shearing of the
large flocks on the other side of the river is not over yet, so Mr Devlin, Mr
Robertson and Mr Cressall could none of them come into the head station. Mr
Taylor managed to come over twenty miles on Christmas morning, carrying before
him on his saddle a hind-quarter of mutton, which he had begged, borrowed or
stolen from somewhere for a Christmas dinner. All attempts to shoot ducks or
turkeys failed: We have had a great many lately, but on Christmas Eve they
entirely declined to &quot;come and be killed&quot;.</p>

<p>Mr Woodward, a gentleman who is
camping with cattle on the other side of the Broken River, was invited over,
and he came early in the morning and bestowed his company on us for the day. He
has been rather a pleasant neighbour for the last two months--riding over to
see us about once a week, and I am sorry he is leaving the district. He goes to
Port Denison with Biddulph tomorrow on his way to Sydney.</p>

<p>Well, he, Mr Taylor, Mr Hedgeland,
Beckford, with Biddulph and overseers, made up the Christmas party. We dined at
eight (we have got later and later as the days have lengthened). The mutton was
stuffed, and was rather approved of, being the first we have had since we came
here--for squatters never kill sheep. Tom made a very superior plum pudding,
apple tart and custard, and any quantity of tea completed our dinner, which I
have described to you, that you may not think we are starved in the bush.</p>

<p>Christmas Day was frightfully hot,
and there was thunder about, which made it oppressive; otherwise we do not care
much for mere heat now, but a cool breeze sprang up in the evening as usual,
and we sat on the veranda and were rather merry, and drank to our absent
friends in lime juice, which the gentlemen warmed with a little brandy.
Biddulph brought up two bottles in his valise from Port Denison for the
occasion. He sent some to the shepherds in pickle bottles.</p>

<p>I thought very much of you on
Christmas Day, and of my last Christmas at home. Do you remember how bright and
cold it was? And how we went out on Christmas Eve and bought a great branch of
holly and dressed the drawing-room? Here we hung up over the pictures some
Australian mistletoe, a pretty parasite, with bright-yellow drooping
branches--like willow in the autumn--which grows in the gum-trees here.
Beckford Simpson, Mr Devlin's nephew, nearly broke his neck in climbing for it,
as a branch gave way, and he only saved himself by catching the trunk of the
gum-tree and sliding down.<br>
&nbsp;On Friday Mr Taylor and Mr Woodward departed again after lunch, and
tomorrow, when Biddulph is gone, we shall be a very small party--only Mr
Hedgeland and Beckford in the house besides Annie and me. All the others are wanted
at the new sheep station that is forming on the other side of the Bowen, twenty
miles off.</p>

<p>You used to say at Danehill that
&quot;Rachel cometh with the sheep&quot;, and you might say so literally if you
were here, for I am generally to be seen walking about with a quart pot full of
milk and a train of nine lambs after me. They are such gentle helpless
creatures that I am very fond of them, though it is rather a trouble to feed
them three times a day.</p>

<p>To my great horror one of them broke
his leg a few days ago. Tom knocked down one of the veranda benches upon him as
he was bringing in dinner in the dark. Mr Taylor bound it up with splints and
he hops about on three legs and does not seem to mind at all. Lamb's bones
unite very quickly. The lame lamb is called Absalom, because he was found in
the creek caught in a tree, not by his hair certainly, as it is of the
shortest, but by his legs. One of the shearers found him and brought him to me
nearly dead, but I got him round, and he was very flourishing till this accident
befell him.</p>

<p>On the evening before Christmas Day
Annie and I were taking a walk in the bush, and Lion, the great bloodhound, who
always goes with us, was trotting along in front when he suddenly stopped and
started back, and right in the middle of the path we saw a large brown snake.
It coiled itself up and always faced Lion as he danced round and round it in a
frantic state of mind between desire to kill it and a wholesome dread of its
fangs.</p>

<p>I was rather afraid to go near it,
and still more afraid that Lion would get himself bitten, so at last I made a
dive and dragged him forcibly off by the ear, when he yelped dismally and the
snake took the opportunity of gliding off among the grass.</p>

<p>He was about four feet long, and
those brown snakes are very venomous. A black snake nine feet long was killed
at Port Denison while Biddulph was there, but the snakes are not very numerous
in this district. That is the only one we have seen in all our walks.</p>

<p>Our last pet was a young curlew,
which Mr Taylor caught and brought in one day. Such a pretty creature, with
long bill and long legs and bright eyes and grey downy feathers. We kept it for
some days and it was getting tame, but one day Lion lay down within reach of
its tether and I suppose it must have walked over him, and he put his great paw
upon it, very likely by accident, for we found it unable to stand and it died.
Lion is very good-natured to his fellow occupants of the veranda in general.
The lambs caper over him, and he only utters a faint growl of remonstrance.
Sometimes he licks them all over. He is a great terror to us when we have clean
dresses on out walking, for he just cools himself in a waterhole, then rolls in
the dust and finally becomes affectionate and comes slobbering up to be patted,
and the result to a clean dress may be imagined. He is a most ferocious-looking
dog, with his deep bloodshot eyes and great hanging ears and lips. I think the
very look of him is a protection if one wanted it.</p>

<p>Mr Hedgeland has just been making
for the veranda two of the easy-chairs called &quot;squatter's delights&quot;.
They are made of two straight poles, which are leant against the wall of the
house ladder-wise. These are held together by two cross-bars, and to the bars
is nailed a strip of strong canvas, such as we use for wool-bagging, and this
forms the seat and back of the chair. The materials are simple enough, but I
think it is the most comfortable kind of easy-chair I know. American chairs are
nothing to it, as they do not yield as the canvas does. Try it if you want a garden
chair.</p>

<p>No rain yet, and the country gets
browner. Most of the sheep have been sent across the river, where there is
better feed. We think nothing of the thermometer being 95, as it generally is
that. If it gets to 100 we say it is hot. It goes down to 70 at night
sometimes, as we know by Mr Hedgeland's registering thermometer.</p>

<p>It is wonderful how soon you get
used to heat. I quite thrive in it as if it was &quot;my native air&quot;.
Annie feels it more, but she is quite well, and Biddulph does not mind it at all.
They say this is a much hotter summer than last was. I cannot think how the
trees keep so green, but they are most brilliant green. The bush flowers are
all over, and we shall have none now till autumn.</p>

<p>Your most affectionate sister,</p>

<p>RACHEL HENNING</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>THE FIRE AT ROSS'S FARM<br>
From: &quot;Short Stories in Prose and Verse&quot; by Henry Lawson<br>
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0607911.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks06/0607911.txt</a></p>

<p>The squatter saw his pastures wide<br>
&nbsp;Decrease, as one by one<br>
The farmers moving to the west<br>
&nbsp;Selected on his run;<br>
Selectors took the water up<br>
&nbsp;And all the black soil round;<br>
The best grass-land the squatter had<br>
&nbsp;Was spoilt by Ross's Ground.</p>

<p>Now many schemes to shift old Ross<br>
&nbsp;Had racked the squatter's brains,<br>
But Sandy had the stubborn blood<br>
&nbsp;Of Scotland in his veins;<br>
He held the land and fenced it in,<br>
&nbsp;He cleared and ploughed the soil,<br>
And year by year a richer crop<br>
&nbsp;Repaid him for his toil.</p>

<p>Between the homes for many years<br>
&nbsp;The devil left his tracks:<br>
The squatter pounded Ross's stock,<br>
&nbsp;And Sandy pounded Black's.<br>
A well upon the lower run<br>
&nbsp;Was filled with earth and logs,<br>
And Black laid baits about the farm<br>
&nbsp;To poison Ross's dogs.</p>

<p>It was, indeed, a deadly feud<br>
&nbsp;Of class and creed and race;<br>
But, yet, there was a Romeo<br>
&nbsp;And a Juliet in the case;<br>
And more than once across the flats,<br>
&nbsp;Beneath the Southern Cross,<br>
Young Robert Black was seen to ride<br>
&nbsp;With pretty Jenny Ross.</p>

<p>One Christmas time, when months of
drought<br>
&nbsp;Had parched the western creeks,<br>
The bush-fires started in the north<br>
&nbsp;And travelled south for weeks.<br>
At night along the river-side<br>
&nbsp;The scene was grand and strange--<br>
The hill-fires looked like lighted streets<br>
&nbsp;Of cities in the range.</p>

<p>The cattle-tracks between the trees<br>
&nbsp;Were like long dusky aisles,<br>
And on a sudden breeze the fire<br>
&nbsp;Would sweep along for miles;<br>
Like sounds of distant musketry<br>
&nbsp;It crackled through the brakes,<br>
And o'er the flat of silver grass<br>
&nbsp;It hissed like angry snakes.</p>

<p>It leapt across the flowing streams<br>
&nbsp;And raced o'er pastures broad;<br>
It climbed the trees and lit the boughs<br>
&nbsp;And through the scrubs it roared.<br>
The bees fell stifled in the smoke<br>
&nbsp;Or perished in their hives,<br>
And with the stock the kangaroos<br>
&nbsp;Went flying for their lives.</p>

<p>The sun had set on Christmas Eve,<br>
&nbsp;When, through the scrub-lands wide,<br>
Young Robert Black came riding home<br>
&nbsp;As only natives ride.<br>
He galloped to the homestead door<br>
&nbsp;And gave the first alarm:<br>
'The fire is past the granite spur,<br>
&nbsp;'And close to Ross's farm.'</p>

<p>'Now, father, send the men at once,<br>
&nbsp;They won't be wanted here;<br>
Poor Ross's wheat is all he has<br>
&nbsp;To pull him through the year.'<br>
'Then let it burn,' the squatter said;<br>
&nbsp;'I'd like to see it done--<br>
I'd bless the fire if it would clear<br>
&nbsp;Selectors from the run.</p>

<p>'Go if you will,' the squatter said,<br>
&nbsp;'You shall not take the men--<br>
Go out and join your precious friends,<br>
&nbsp;And don't come here again.'<br>
'I won't come back,' young Robert cried,<br>
&nbsp;And, reckless in his ire,<br>
He sharply turned his horse's head<br>
&nbsp;And galloped towards the fire.</p>

<p>And there, for three long weary
hours,<br>
&nbsp;Half-blind with smoke and heat,<br>
Old Ross and Robert fought the flames<br>
&nbsp;That neared the ripened wheat.<br>
The farmer's hand was nerved by fears<br>
&nbsp;Of danger and of loss;<br>
And Robert fought the stubborn foe<br>
&nbsp;For the love of Jenny Ross.</p>

<p>But serpent-like the curves and
lines<br>
&nbsp;Slipped past them, and between,<br>
Until they reached the bound'ry where<br>
&nbsp;The old coach-road had been.<br>
'The track is now our only hope,<br>
&nbsp;There we must stand,' cried Ross,<br>
'For nought on earth can stop the fire<br>
&nbsp;If once it gets across.'</p>

<p>Then came a cruel gust of wind,<br>
&nbsp;And, with a fiendish rush,<br>
The flames leapt o'er the narrow path<br>
&nbsp;And lit the fence of brush.<br>
'The crop must burn!' the farmer cried,<br>
&nbsp;'We cannot save it now,'<br>
And down upon the blackened ground<br>
&nbsp;He dashed the ragged bough.</p>

<p>But wildly, in a rush of hope,<br>
&nbsp;His heart began to beat,<br>
For o'er the crackling fire he heard<br>
&nbsp;The sound of horses' feet.<br>
'Here's help at last,' young Robert cried,<br>
&nbsp;And even as he spoke<br>
The squatter with a dozen men<br>
&nbsp;Came racing through the smoke.</p>

<p>Down on the ground the stockmen
jumped<br>
&nbsp;And bared each brawny arm,<br>
They tore green branches from the trees<br>
&nbsp;And fought for Ross's farm;<br>
And when before the gallant band<br>
&nbsp;The beaten flames gave way,<br>
Two grimy hands in friendship joined--<br>
&nbsp;And it was Christmas Day.</p>

<p>* * *</p>

<p>JEST 'FORE CHRISTMAS<br>
by Eugene Field (1850-1895)</p>

<p>I am not sure where I fist saw this
poem. I cannot find it in any of our ebooks. It can be found on the internet,
along with more of Field's poetry.</p>

<p>Father calls me William, sister
calls me Will,<br>
Mother calls me Willie, but the fellers call me Bill!<br>
Mighty glad I ain't a girl-- ruther be a boy,<br>
Without them sashes, curls, an' things that's worn by Fauntleroy!<br>
Love to chawnk green apples an' go swimmin' in the lake--<br>
Hate to take the castor-ile they give for belly-ache!<br>
'Most all the time the whole year round, there ain't no flies on me,<br>
But jest 'fore Christmas, I'm as good as I kin be!</p>

<p>Got yeller dog named Sport, sick him
on the cat;<br>
First thing she knows she doesn't know where she is at!<br>
Got a clipper sled, an' when us kids goes out to slide,<br>
'Long comes the grocery cart, an' we all hook a ride!<br>
But sometimes when the grocery man is worrited an' cross,<br>
He reaches at us with his whip, an' larrups up his hoss,<br>
An' then I laff an' holler, &quot;Oh, ye never teched ME!&quot;<br>
But jest 'fore Christmas, I'm as good as I kin be!</p>

<p>Gran'ma says she hopes that when I
git to be a man,<br>
I'll be a missionarer like her oldest brother, Dan,<br>
As was et up by the cannibuls that lives in Ceylon's Isle,<br>
Where every prospeck pleases, an' only man is vile!<br>
But gran'ma she has never been to see a Wild West show,<br>
Nor read the Life of Daniel Boone, or else I guess she'd know<br>
That Buff'lo Bill and cowboys is good enough for me!<br>
EXCEP' jest 'fore Christmas, when I'm as good as I kin be!</p>

<p>And then old Sport he hangs around,
so solemn-like an' still,<br>
His eyes they keep a-sayin':&nbsp; &quot;What;s the matter, little Bill?&quot;<br>
The old cat sneaks down off her perch an' wonders what's become<br>
Of them two enemies of hern that used to make things hum!<br>
But I am perlite an' 'tend so earnestly to biz,<br>
That mother says to father: &quot;How improved our Willie is!&quot;<br>
But father, havin' been a boy hisself, suspicions me<br>
When, jest 'fore Christmas, I'm as good as I kin be!</p>

<p>For Christmas, with its lots an'
lots of candies, cakes, an' toys,<br>
Was made, they say, for proper kids an' not for naughty boys;<br>
So wash yer face an' brush yer hair, an' mind yer p's an' q's,<br>
An' don't bust out yer pantaloons, an' don't wear out yer shoes;<br>
Say :Yessum&quot; to the ladies, an' &quot;Yessur&quot; to the men,<br>
An' when they's company, don't pass yer plate for pie again;<br>
But, thinkin' of the things yer'd like to see upon that tree,<br>
Jest 'fore Christmas be as good as yer kin be!</p>

<p>LAST MONTH'S POSTINGS<br>
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br>
A list of all the books we provide is available from <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/plusfifty.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/plusfifty.html</a><br>
Check there to see if there are other works by the authors listed below.</p>

<p>-- NOVEMBER POSTINGS --</p>

<pre>Nov 2008 The Courts of the Morning, John Buchan&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080136xx.xxx] 1718A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801361.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801361.txt</a> or .zip
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801361h.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801361h.html</a>

Nov 2008 Sketches from the Karen Hills, Alonzo Bunker&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080135xx.xxx] 1717A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801351.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801351.txt</a> or .zip

Nov 2008 Anglo-Karen Dictionary, Jonathan Wade&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080134xx.xxx] 1716A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801341p.pdf" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801341p.pdf</a>

Nov 2008 A Voyage to Establish a Colony, James H Tuckey&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080133xx.xxx] 1715A
[Author: James Hingston Tuckey]
[Title: A Voyage to Establish a Colony at Port Philip in Bass's Strait]
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801331.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801331.txt</a> or .zip

Nov 2008 Prelude to Waking, Miles Franklin&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080132xx.xxx] 1714A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801321.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801321.txt</a> or .zip

Nov 2008 Old Blastus of Bandicoot, Miles Franklin&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080131xx.xxx] 1713A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801311.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801311.txt</a> or .zip

Nov 2008 Bring the Monkey, Miles Franklin&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080130xx.xxx] 1712A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801301.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801301.txt</a> or .zip
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801301h.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801301h.html</a>

Nov 2008 A Self-Made Thief, Hulbert Footner&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080129xx.xxx] 1711A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801291.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801291.txt</a>

Nov 2008 Ten Creeks Run, Miles Franklin&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080128xx.xxx] 1710A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801281.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801281.txt</a> or .zip

Nov 2008 Back to Bool Bool, Miles Franklin&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [080127xx.xxx] 1709A
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801271.txt" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801271.txt</a> or .zip
<a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801271h.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/ebooks08/0801271h.html</a>&nbsp;</pre>

<p>To visit the Project Gutenberg of
Australia web site, go to <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au</a></p>

<p>To contact us, go to <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/contact.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/contact.html</a></p>

<p>To get HELP with downloading the
ebooks available from Project Gutenberg of Australia go to <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/help.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/help.html</a></p>

<p>To view past newsletters go to <a href="http://gutenberg.net.au/oldnews.html" rel="nofollow">http://gutenberg.net.au/oldnews.html</a></p>

<p>Tell a friend to subscribe to this
newsletter at <a href="http://www.zanehost.com/?p=subscribe&amp;id=4" rel="nofollow">http://www.zanehost.com/?p=subscribe&amp;id=4</a></p>

<p>--------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br>
Project Gutenberg of Australia<br>
a treasure-trove of literature<br>
treasure-trove n. treasure found hidden with no evidence of ownership.<br>
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>OTHER INFORMATION<br>
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br>
Newsletter Editor: Colin Choat</p>

</body>

</html>
